Here it is!
This is where the channel
encourages everyone to perform a
little mantra to remember that
[music]
takes away all people's problems and
gives them help, and this is a
tradition of
reading manga in a whispering way
throughout the day.
Keep your matcha mantra, don't
lose it when you
get on the plane, don't leave it at the
airport, and use it
while you're walking.
I'll give you $100.
Everyone, wake up!
If you can tell me two
requirements to have a
truly powerful mantra, who calls upon the tradition
[music] to
uphold your morality and
receive Masa from a person, a
teacher called a true master.
How do you get $100?
When you
answer the question correctly, meet Ms.
Chide and receive the money from her. That's
right,
[music],
you must have the
mantra, you must be
encouraged by a
true lineage to get the mantra,
and the second thing is...  You must
maintain
your morality,
mainly the ten virtuous deeds,
which have two types of
mantras: the
Bodhisattva morality and the Tantric morality.
When you do this, it means you
should recite your mantra so
you can remember it. It's to always remember that
you will give to others, give to
others, bring them happiness, and take away their problems.
You can do this in
a small way, like at the airport
when you're
approaching customs.
Here, I'll give you some fair,
some mantras that I've already talked about.
Let's say, "Okay, I'll give
you some verses from ancient scriptures
so you can use them as
your little mantras." And
again,
believe me, there are many
wonderful stories about the Buddha, how he
became a Buddha,
stories about how he
gave his body to you,
and we've had
many efforts in Mongolia, and Johny has had three
projects.  Mongolia and trying to
classify and store
300,000 books and I think that
jumping said, "Look, I can give
you
some of the verses from the Golden Light."
You don't really know, you don't
really understand that news. Actually,
if you can just recite the verses
that
we give you from the Lama sofa
that we do every time
we do a retreat here, and on the first night
we give you, we give
you Lim, and he
says, "If you can, with it from Loner,
some teachers on the path
can kill you to the verses from lamachiva to
perform
like a mantra, and instead of
you read and vandal,
instead of reading 100,000,
they will perform the
Retinue like this verse, like a
mantra, like a million times, on
both sides, like they are
coming.
I have a model for you, are you
ready? This is
Lama
do Paris
Yesterday,
and I want to say a little bit about the profession. He
was the first person who taught me how to wear shoes
in my life."  He
and I are a very wonderful person,
a very wonderful teacher who
helped bring Buddhism to the West.
The fact is,
we grew up in a country where we
didn't know about Buddhism, we
never heard of meditation, and
there were some great teachers
from Tibet in refugee camps,
and they went to the West. They were
very brave teachers, they
learned English,
and they helped
people. And
I want to think about those years, the
years when the
Titanic was crashing into Pham Van Troi,
and the Westerners were like
icebergs,
and then some brave teachers from
Tibet came to the West and started teaching,
like the
Titanic. And
it wasn't easy. Because there was a
huge cultural gap
between Tibet and the West,
and some of
these special Lamas came and
tried to teach the
Kitty people in the West.
Lama Super,
and he was a DC, they
came to the refugee camps.
You can see
he was a very funny person, very
good at speaking.  Joking aside, I remember a story
about some offices in San
Francisco, and they said that two people gave
me a pair of orange pants that broke,
and that day I bought a pair of orange pants
that I wore out on the day
they came out. He taught at the University of San Francisco, and I thought about it, and he taught Westerners, and a few, and there were a few hundred of them. So, you see, some teachers from Tibet who
broke through the iceberg of American people,
and I really didn't have
much money. They were trying to teach
at the University of San Francisco
during the hitty period,
during the worst of the North,
and they had to be very brave to be able to
teach in a place that was full of
hitty people
about Buddhism. And they tried very hard, they tried very hard,
and I remember one day they came
together to meet my teacher,
and I was very excited,
and they went to a Mongolian monastery.
Lambda Dec was very funny,
and he was the complete opposite, 100%
serious. He was a  The
reincarnation of a
very tall lama,
born
in the
Everest region, in a
small village on Everest,
and
then to a refugee camp,
and the only thing is, how many
[music]
and I got, about 100 or so,
and he dedicated his time
to doing that,
and he's here, the Lamac, and they're like
500, there's a magnetic pull between them,
and they've built the biggest
Buddhist organization in the West together.
They've worked very hard. Lama
Dec
had heart disease for many years,
and
they still continued day after day, refusing to rest.
His student,
Maxima, continued for many years,
and
he was
8 years ago, but he didn't
stop. And day after day,
while I was doing a retreat and
teaching,
when I was teaching about the Diamond Sutra for the
first time,
he told me, "
And
you should not sleep,
meet with your students all night and
day,
and people gave me things."  The advice was
during my three-year retreat,
and then suddenly someone knocked on
my door at 3 a.m.,
and when I got there with Christy,
she said, "You want to practice the Dharma," and
she said, "Your senses are
connected to your nose
and its object is the universe, the things you
hear, the
things you see,
and it's like women
and your senses are like
men's, and in connection with each other."
She gave an example, "Good luck,
and have a wonderful day." I
know, I
heard that there are ways you
shouldn't do it, but you should do it the
other way, and I will support you.
That's how it was done back then,
and we've lost a teacher, that
was great,
and that generation
has disappeared,
and we're very lucky that
we had them help,
and now it's difficult, we have to
pass it on, transmit it, and
be courageous, as if
we have to keep it alive.  Keep the
Dharma spreading,
bless your child, your master, your
teacher's compassion,
invite
all beings, room for all beings, invite
happiness, all their
suffering, all their obstacles to all beings,
your mothers,
buy into yourself
so that your goodness can
help
and your happiness can be sent to
everyone,
help them be happy,
use every action and activity
of the day, I always think about driving
back to Tusson, using it
like your practice,
you interact with other drivers,
it's very interesting,
use it as a way to practice
during that
traffic jam,
then he mentioned some interesting points
that we can check,
we can use
his life story in cappella, we
can use that as an example,
and then he said,
now there is a very important word in
Buddhism, Always. In Tibetan it
means wind.
It is one of the elements, cartoon
Nemo, country of wind and fire,
always has  It means wind,
but it's also a word, it
also means air or prana.
We will
delve into a principle that is the later part of
Vajrayana Buddhism. Here, it's the diamond of
nitrogen, like water flowing under the
ice. Do you truly understand it?
I've been teaching
about the diamond from
under the ice for 30 years, 13 of which are like water
flowing beneath the ice.
Let it control your Pana, let it
flow up and
send through your breath.
It's very profound. Here, it connects
with
giving and receiving, the practice of giving and receiving,
taking away other people's problems
and giving them what is coming from
you.
That becomes a secret practice, a
practice according to Vajrayana,
using your prana, using
your breath. It's not Vana, but
prana. It ends with connecting with
your breath very closely, and we
will focus on
your breath.
Today is a prana
Yamaha, which means the practice of
...  What is it? Like
[music]
trying to make something happen inside
you. Ayama, it can also be
read as controlling your breath.
Yama means control, like,
it also means lord of death.
I'll tell you why it's so
complicated.
In the past, Yamaha was the human rope
so you could control it,
and Yamaha came in pairs, consisting of two things. You
see, there's a pair of them, and night,
and there are two
gods connected to them. Day
symbolizes night, symbolizing the beating,
like the loss of a loved one.
It's a day and night. We have a
pair, like a
pair of horse bridle, that's Yama,
and the king of death is
called Yama.
And if you can write, because the king
can end the king of death.
Yamata,
Yemen, Taka.
If you can kill the lord of
death,
we practice here and maybe
learn it.
What's the rest?
Alada. Beat death to death.
That's part of Hatary.
It takes 2 years to teach it, and we
are...  In between, and
it will be the next program of the
Yoga academy's filming which will start
in September
and we will teach about coloranda from here
and anyway, here,
let's use prana,
use your breath exercises
and of course there is a deep connection
between breath and your state of mind.
When you are worried, you breathe very
fast, very quickly. When you are busy
all day and you are not focused on
people, you also breathe very
abnormally. You don't when you
do
this work day after day, hour after hour,
you can check your current situation,
check how you are breathing
and if you really practice giving and
receiving
from time to time, it will
affect your breath. So
observe your breath and when
your breath is
weak, it is not gentle,
it means something is
happening, something is wrong in your mind,
there is a problem with your mind.
If you practice  By focusing on the practice hour
after hour with your small practice,
you are also
working with your brana, and
you will feel brighter and
calmer, and your breath will be lighter,
going through your left and right nostrils.
You don't have to remember it.
I had a student many years ago, Nitro,
and every time I taught him about it,
he would tell me, "Don't teach
me anymore." I asked why, and
he said, "There's a place where I
feel guilty about it. I
'll feel guilty all day if I
don't do it." You should be
careful with it.
Take the instructions from the
retreat that you find interesting.
Feel interested in it, and
use it for a few weeks.
Really, just let it go. Just let it go because
you can't remember
everything, you can't practice
everything. If you try to practice
everything, your breath
will become disordered,
and you'll be like, "
Why?"  The teacher will be teaching hundreds of
different practices. I want you to
connect with one of them and
use it for a while,
and don't get overwhelmed.
Just choose one of them. That's why
they give you
hundreds of practices; there are hundreds of
different personalities,
different people.
This might
suit one person, that might
suit another. But if you
hear something that appeals to
you, then practice it.
Don't feel confused about everything
you hear in class.
I think this will connect
you throughout the day, and you'll develop the
habit of observing others
and seeing what people are doing.
Observe the doors, serve them tea,
and I think these are small things like
parana breathing and
your breathing.
When you have this intention,
you should help yourself to
observing people, serving people,
things like that.
Helping strangers, right?
And I want to thank Nobita for coming
today. My
mother, my stepmother, had a heart attack and I
had to go to a nursing home
and there were hundreds of people there, they were lying
in beds
and I talked to another family
and they were so sweet and so wonderful, like
Buddhists.
And usually I'm very shy,
I'm not shy about teaching but I'm very
shy about talking to people
like, "Where are you from?"
and this family is taking care of their parents
and like the exercise, it's so
cute, so wonderful, it's
going on.
You practice anywhere, wherever
you are,
and you connect with your system.
If you can remember, if
you are breathing abnormally, it
could be that you are anxious, you
are frustrated, or you are not
awake, your body will not be
smooth,
and it is said that when you
observe your breath
and the signs that
things are happening. See you soon.
Hour after hour, and as
you practice, you'll get pretty good,
and you'll create a memory card that you
're giving kindness and
good things to others.
You're taking away
other people's problems,
so don't
forget to focus on it. As long as
you're breathing, you can
do this
if you give it.
Maybe connect with your breath,
connect your breath to
your practice, then your breath
will remind you of success
throughout the day.
Now I'm ready for
that cowboy.
$100
[music].
Why the cowboy for people
related to the discussion with me
today? Because the
whale. That's
how Pana and thinking go together,
then the horse and our thinking,
like the cowboy.
Remember to give money to
your cowboy,
then go to China, and I think
I need two, three, four words about that to
inspire.
This is a practice.  Increasing the level of proficiency
in the Yoga class at the Yoga academy
and
he... Everyone asks me how to
pronounce it and here it is. I
mean, this is the
rana wind or the sign, it
means
our minds just mean they flow
together like, for
example, a
cowboy with a horse. I
heard some great news. Here
they built a business in the
gas business. They built an
ice cream shop
like a pilgrimage
and then they closed it, which was very
sad, and recently
they reopened it,
opened an
Indian restaurant
[music],
and they came and they made Indian food
that was like 40 or 50 years ago, and we
ate it, and it was very great,
and I really liked it.
We often go to
that ice cream shop, and we sit on the
door on the horse,
and the horse is tied to a
post there,
and we
eat ice cream and the cowboy runs up,
and he gets down, and he comes out with
a big gun, and he...
My friend asked if they were
filming a movie.
I said this isn't a movie, this is
real,
there's a real gun.
You have to be nice to them, and we'll
meet a tall guy,
and you have to find out for yourself,
don't annoy them.
I asked why they brought a gun
down with them, they
can shoot,
and
think about the cowboy and the
inner point here is
the intention that we help
others, they go together
like the cowboy on
horseback.
Who is the horse and who is the cowboy?
$25. If there are two choices.
And sometimes I still feel
confused and mixed up. Who is the horse? The cowboy is your
breath, the horse
is your mind. The
horse is prana
and is reflected by your breath.
If the flow of prana inside
you is not running smoothly,
your breath will be
irregular. The
two are...  Your breath
and your horse are your thoughts,
and specifically your awareness,
that is your poet of not being up
all day. Every opportunity you have
to care for someone,
every opportunity you have to do something kind
to someone,
have a deep intention within
yourself to care for others.
You can force yourself to take care of yourself
first, and that's very
difficult.
I feel I have to comply, but
sometimes I let it go and I start thinking
about myself, and really,
when you take care of yourself first,
but those are a few small exceptions
throughout the day. If so,
but you must remember to take care of
others first. Of course, not
everyone likes the way I am,
and for many years, my wife has been a
master at this.
If you take care of others first,
care for others first, it's
really, really amazing. It
makes your life, it makes
your whole life. The above is the meaning.
More than
anything you learn, not
entirely, not any meditation practice you
do, it doesn't matter, just
focus on others, take care of
them first.
If that's the only thing you
go through, you'll learn from the center, I'll
learn what the scriptures are, that will help
your life succeed and you
will be extremely happy.
We always struggle to be
happy and take care of ourselves
first, and that won't work. Those
are stupid ideas, a
stupid strategy, it's
human nature, and you have to fight against it.
Not because of moral issues,
blah blah, but the only way
you can be happy is to
take care of others
first. The more you do
it, the happier you will be.
You don't lose
anything; you only lose when you take
care of yourself first.
This attitude
has something about the horse and the
cowboy: the horse is your breath, your lifeblood,
and the cowboy...  Breath is
your breath, your thoughts, so who is in
control?
Who is in control? I'm in Chisson,
someone said
there's a lake in
Printon, they built the lake,
and I'm in the hill rowing,
and we row up and down,
and we can
[music]
ride horses around there
[music],
and I rode a horse once,
it was a long horse.  Whatever they could find,
and I went with my father, and they said
I could do it,
and it was very interesting.
I saw some
horse movies, and they had horses, and I sat on the
horse, and I kicked it, and it went
very fast, and I had to stop it. I was
trying to stop it. There was something that
bit its mouth, and when you
pull the rope, it hurts, and it
stops, and it
and I fell down,
and I never rode a horse again
in my whole life. Throughout
my life, I
'm talking about this. Sometimes the
horse
won't be controlled. If
your breath is interrupted,
your mind will follow.
Sometimes
when the cowboy loses control, it
's the horse's performance.
Sometimes the mind takes
control of your mind. Goodbye, you
control grana, and sometimes you get out of
control of your mind.
Sometimes the
horse takes control, and sometimes the
human takes control.
The three means that
if you lose control of your breath,
your mind will
become disordered. If your mind is
disordered,
your body will follow suit. And if
you can't observe your mind,
you can observe
your physical form. That
relates to the physical body, so you'll find it easier to
observe. If
you don't control your mind,
or your mind
becomes unhappy,
then you must have the
ability to observe your mind.
And if your breath becomes crazy, you
can trust
your mind is following it. And if you
observe your breath on a
bad day, you can't believe you're
observing it. When you can't observe
your mind, you might be afraid.
Because it's related, and it
will follow.
If you practice it well,
what does it mean
now? You won't  Forget about taking
off your clothes,
control your Ferrari
like a cowboy.
If you're
really good at observing
your breath, you'll find it easier to do those
faster car maneuvers. Remember that
everyone has an equal right to
happiness, and then
switch from taking care of
yourself first to taking care of others
first, and you won't lose anything.
That's the problem you struggle with
throughout your life when you
strive to take care of yourself first,
because if you don't
care about others first, then you wo
n't get anything.
That's the biggest mistake you
can make. If
you believe you're not taking care of
yourself first, then you wo
n't get anything. You have to
take care of yourself and others first. Believe in
that, and you won't
lose anything. Don't be foolish.
This is a very
common word, not as common
as a large machine,
but a medium-sized machine for children.  In
Tibetan, it's a set of words related to miracles,
like Roku. And it means
practicing and taking care of yourself, taking care of
others first, like a
big machine at the back of your life. The body,
like
Larva, comes from,
like a big machine, and it
means like a machine to
produce happiness.
Thank you, big guys,
and
take the seed from the shell.
They are comparing the pre-body to
that big machine,
and it's a machine that creates happiness in
your life
because taking care of others first,
to slim and lens.
That's a big machine
that can bring you happiness, that
's a machine that creates happiness, a
happiness factory.
Then we'll
stop this class here,
and we'll continue.
Let's go from here to the inspector,
and he'll go into the inspector a
little deeper, and the inspector, and we'll
come back to the next class.
See you in half an hour.